Tor Stahl

Mill Valley, California | 415.272.4033 | tstahl@wiredbarn.com

Overview

Senior product and technology leader focused on analytical software development. Specialized in healthcare, mobile applications, marketing, advertising, financial services and related data-driven technologies.

Ability to bridge a variety of disciplines from a detail level technical focus to a high-level management view. Excellent communication and presentation skills.

A detail understanding of the dynamics of developing Software as a Service (SaaS), enterprise class software, cloud computing infrastructure and software licensing models.

Experience

SENIOR DIRECTOR, BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE & ANALYTICS | PRACTICE FUSION | OCTOBER 2015 - PRESENT

- · Management of a team of data engineers and data scientists.
- · Responsible for analytics supporting strategy and day-to-day operations of all Practice Fusion lines of business.
- Development of engagement metrics and related KPIs used to segment the user base for Financial Modeling,
 Marketing and Sales efforts.
- · Product feature reporting and analysis.
- Development of dashboard and reports used widely across the business to monitor the health of the business, uncover trends and simulate outcomes based on business strategies.
- · Development of provider NPI matching and attribution algorithms used to enhance internal data assets.
- Competitive research using third party data sources such as SK&A to enhance provider profiling for business strategy initiatives.
- · Member of the company Leadership Team.

SENIOR PROGRAM MANAGER, DATA SERVICES PLATFORM | PRACTICE FUSION | JULY 2013 – OCTOBER 2015

- Managed data related deliveries for Meaningful Use Certification in 2013. Development and testing efforts related to the Clinical Document Data Architecture (CCDA) HL7 XML standard to support Transitions of Care/Referral, Data Portability and View, Download, & Transmit to 3rd Party.
- · Implementation of the Clinical Quality Measures (CQM) and Clinical Decision Support (CDS) applications.
- · Implementation of a multi-terabyte HPAA compliant Netezza data warehousing appliance, Informatica ETL and Tableau Server reporting environments.

TECHNICAL PRODUCT MANAGER, WO ANALYTICS | WIDEORBIT | JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2013

 Manage product road map, vision and release cycles for WIdeOrbit Analytics. Oversee product development team. WO Analytics provides the most powerful suite of advertising management solutions for Media companies.

PRODUCT MANAGER, MOBILE ANALYTICS | MFOUNDRY (CURRENTLY FIS GLOBAL) | JUNE 2010 – JANUARY 2012

• End-to-end product development of a stand-alone Mobile Analytics product: mAnalytics, recognized as the best analytical product in the Mobile Banking industry by Frost & Sullivan

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER, ADVERTISER INSIGHTS | TRIBAL FUSION - EXPONENTIAL | 2009 - 2010

CONSULTANT, PRODUCT/PROJECT MANAGEMENT| NIELSEN MOBILE | 2008 -2009

VICE PRESIDENT OF ANALYTICS | REDWOOD TRUST | 2007 – 2008

CONSULTANT, BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE | VISAGE MOBILE | 2006 –2007

CONSULTANT, BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE AUTODESK | 2004 –2006

CONSULTANT, BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE | CISCO | 2002 –2004

DIRECTOR, DATA WAREHOUSE | NEXTCARD | 2001 – 2002

DIRECTOR, DATA WAREHOUSE | ETOYS | 1999 - 2001

SENIOR MANAGER, CUSTOMER INFORMATION MANAGEMENT | AMERICAN EXPRESS | 1995 – 1999

Skills & Abilities

- · Leadership, Management, Communication
- Tableau Desktop/Server (7+ years continuous)
- · Web Analytics: Mixpanel, Google Analytics
- · Forecasting, predictive modeling R & Python
- · Application Development On-Premise, SaaS
- · Data Warehouse: Informatica/SSIS ETL, Netezza, SQL Server, MongoDB
- · Product Development: PRD, MRD, Rapid Prototyping
- · Collaboration Tools: Confluence, Jira
- · Project Management: Agile, SCRUM, Waterfall
- · Release Planning, Change Management, Defect Management, Product Support and Training

Education

B.S. BUSINESS, MARKETING & MANAGEMENT | 1994 | NORTHEASTERN UNIVERSITY